Teiko Middle School
（ナレーション）
帝光(ていこう)中学 バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも—
Even amidst their brilliant record,
there was a generation of five prodigies
known as the "Generation of Miracles."
10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた“キセキの世代”
黄瀬(きせ)涼太(りょうた)
Kise Ryota.
緑間(みどりま)真太郎(しんたろう)
Midorima Shintaro.
青峰(あおみね)大輝(だいき)
Aomine Daiki.
Murasakibara Atsushi.
紫原 敦(むらさきばらあつし)
Akashi Seijuro.
赤司征十郎(あかしせいじゅうろう)
そして
彼らを脅かす誠凛(せいりん)高校の—
They are threatened by Seirin High's
shadow and light.
影と光
（赤司）君が どくんだ
You're going to move for me.
（高尾(たかお)）なっ…！
（木村(きむら)）おお！
（宮地(みやじ)）なっ…！
Shintaro, you are strong.
（赤司）真太郎 オマエは強い
But you will lose.
（赤司）だが 負ける
たとえ オマエたちでも
僕に逆らうことなど できはしない
Not even you can stand against me.
逆らう者は何人(なんぴと)たりとも—
I never allow those who oppose me
to look down at me.
見下ろすことを許さない
I Will Give Them to You
（火神(かがみ)）諦めてない？
They haven't given up?
（黒子(くろこ)）はい 彼は—
No. He's trying to do something.
何か やろうとしている
（葉山(はやま)）
ここから追い上げるつもりなら—
If they're trying to close the gap
now, they'll need Midorima's threes.
緑間のスリーは不可欠
だけど赤司がついてる以上
どうやったって無理っしょ
But as long as Akashi's
on him, it's impossible.
（小金井(こがねい)）バイオレーション
取られるまで10秒切った
They only have ten seconds before
they receive a violation.
やっぱ攻めあぐねてる？
Do they not know how to attack?
（木吉(きよし)）それもあるだろうが
それ以上に—
I'm sure that's partly true,
but what they're about to attempt
is probably pretty risky.
恐らく これからトライすることは
相当リスキーなんじゃないかな
What do you mean?
（伊月(いづき)）どういうことだ？
Shutoku
Rakuzan
（木吉）
残り時間と点差を考えれば—
Considering the remaining time and point
gap, a single mistake could be fatal.
もはや１つのミスが命取りだ
Hesitation and uncertainty lead to mistakes.
迷いや不安はミスにつながる
In other words, they'll make
their move when they're ready.
つまり動くのは—
覚悟を決めたときだ
Hey, Midorima Shintaro-kun.
（高尾）おーい 緑間真太郎君
Hey. I'm Takao Kazunari.
よう
オレ 高尾和成(かずなり)ってんだ
You're joining the basketball team, right?
バスケ部 入んだろ？
オレも入るんだ よろしくな
Me, too. Nice to meet you.
なぜオレの名を知っているのだよ
How do you know my name?
Everyone who plays basketball
knows your name.
（高尾）バスケやってて
知らねーヤツのほうが少ねえよ
Huh? What's that?
あれ？ それ何？
（緑間）おは朝占いの
今日のラッキーアイテム
Oha Asa fortune's lucky item for the day.
セロハンテープなのだよ
It's tape.
何それ？
Are you serious?
（緑間）何がおかしいのだよ
What's so funny?
いや おかしいでしょ
You don't think it's hilarious
that their lucky item is tape?
ラッキーアイテム セロテ？
しかも流しちゃったけど
語尾も何？
And I forgot to say something,
but what's with the way you talk?
めっちゃウケんだけど
It's freaking hilarious!
（緑間）フン 軽薄そうなヤツだ
He seems frivolous.
My first impression of Takao wasn't good.
高尾に対するオレの第一印象は—
決してよくはなかった
Okay, next! Shuttle run!
（大坪(おおつぼ)）よし 次！ シャトルラン
Yes, sir!
（部員たち）はい！
Run, run, run!
（部員１）走れ 走れ 走れ！
（宮地）
ほら そこ！ 遅れてるぞ！
You're falling behind!
ちゃんと床にタッチしろ！
Touch the floor!
Shutoku's practices were as grueling
as Teiko's, if not more so.
（緑間）秀徳(しゅうとく)の練習は
帝光と同じか—
それ以上に過酷なものだった
Club Resignation Form
中学で腕を鳴らした者が次々と—
Boys who were successful in middle school
quit every day, one after another.
毎日のように辞めていく
ましてや—
Among the first years, not a single
student stayed late to practice.
１年生で練習後に
居残りする者などいなかった
（高尾）ブフッ…！
What's so funny?
何がおかしいのだよ
（高尾）
いやぁ 何度見てもスゲーし—
It never ceases to amaze me.
それに高すぎ シュート
Seriously, your shots are way too high.
Shut up. Don't get in my way.
（緑間）うるさい 邪魔をするな
Sorry, sorry.
（高尾）ああ ワリィ ワリィ
いや 否定する気はないぜ マジ
I don't mean to put you down.
フン
Anyway, what do you think you're doing?
それより どういうつもりなのだよ
Huh?
最近 オレが残っているときは
必ずオマエもいる
Recently you've always been
around when I stay late.
それに練習中
何かと張り合ってくる節がある
You seem to compete with
me during practice, too.
Do you bear some kind
of animosity against me?
オレに特別な敵意でもあるのか？
Sort of.
まあな
I guess you don't remember me.
（高尾）つか やっぱ
思い出してはもらえねーか
I played against you once
in middle school and lost.
オレ 中学のとき—
一度 オマエとやって
負けてんだけど
I kept practicing after I
quit out of frustration.
悔しくて引退した後も
練習続けて—
When I finally got into high school,
そんで いざ高校進学したら—
the guy I swore to defeat became my teammate.
絶対 倒すと決めた相手が—
チームメイトとして
目の前にいやがる
It's laughable.
笑うわ マジ
But there's no point in being hostile now.
けど今さら敵意なんて持っても
意味ねえしな
むしろオマエにオレのことを
認めさせたかった
If anything, I just wanted
you to acknowledge me.
Maybe that's why it seemed
like I was competing with you.
張り合ってるように見えたのは
そのせいかな
（緑間）
なぜ言わなかったのだよ？
Why didn't you say anything?
What?
あい？
Why are you laughing?
なぜ笑う？
（高尾）そっちこそ なんでだよ
Are you serious? You want me to tell you?
言うの？ オレが
“僕 君にボコボコにされてから
頑張ってきたんだ 認めて”って？
"After you destroyed me, I worked
really hard! Please acknowledge me!"
Talk about lame!
ダッセー
そんなつもりねえだろうけど
むしろ まだ認めんなよ
I'm sure I don't have to tell you not
to, but don't acknowledge me yet.
I'll practice harder than you.
オレはただ オマエより練習する
I'm just doing what I decided to do.
自分で決めたことを
やってるだけだ
そのうち思わず
うなるようなパスしてやっから—
Eventually I'll send you a pass
that will impress even you!
Don't you forget, Shin-chan!
覚えとけよ！ 真ちゃん
Don't call me that.
It's too familiar, Takao.
その呼び方は
なれなれしいからやめろ
高尾
（緑間）これは賭けだ
This is a gamble.
自分を信じる以上に—
I must trust my teammates
more than I trust myself.
チームメイトを信じる必要がある
オレが人事を尽くすだけでは
足りない
It's not enough for me to do
everything I possibly can.
But I am certain.
だが 不安はない
There isn't a man on this team who hasn't
done everything humanly possible!
このチームに—
人事を尽くしていない者などいない
He's entering his shooting motion.
（黄瀬）ボールを持ってないのに…
Without the ball?
（火神）
シュートモーションに入った？
These guys...
（根武谷(ねぶや)）こいつら…
What is he doing?
（赤司）何をやっている？
Could it be?
まさか…
（日向(ひゅうが)）
空中で取って そのままスリー？
He caught the ball mid-air
and shot a three-pointer?
Is that even possible?
（小金井）ありえんのか？ それ
（木村）よーし！
（宮地）っしゃー！
Yeah!
From that height, even if
Akashi could see the future,
（氷室(ひむろ)）確かに あの高さなら—
たとえ先が見えても
カットできない
he couldn't intercept the shot.
だが難しいとか—
But that was more than just difficult.
そういうレベルの話じゃないぞ
今のは
決めた緑間も当然すごいが
それだけじゃない
Midorima's amazing for making
the shot, but that's not all.
緑間が構えた位置にドンピシャで
パスを入れるなんて—
Passing the ball right into Midorima's
hands takes unbelievable accuracy.
信じられない正確さだ
I can't imagine the old Midorimacchi
doing anything like this.
（黄瀬）こんなの—
今までの緑間っちだったら
考えられないっスね
（森山(もりやま)）え？
What?
Midorimacchi only takes shots
he's absolutely confident in.
緑間っちは本来—
絶対の自信を持ったシュートしか
打とうとしないっス
けど今のは—
But no matter how accurate the pass was,
パスがどんなに正確でも—
通常のシュートより
やはり精度は落ちる
what he just did was less
accurate than a standard shot.
いくら赤司っちに勝つためでも—
He may be trying to beat Akashi,
but he'd never take a shot that might
miss unless he really trusted his teammates.
外れることを覚悟したシュートを
打つなんて—
よっぽどチームメイトを
信頼してねえとしないはずっスよ
リバン！
Rebound!
（根武谷）オッサン
This old dude's still going for rebounds!
この終盤で
また いかついリバウンドしやがる
He's got a lot of stamina!
大したスタミナだぜ
速攻！
Fast break!
（ホイッスル）
（観客１）決めた！ ３本連続！
He made it!
That's three in a row!
Shutoku
Rakuzan
（観客２）
秀徳 一気に差を縮めてきた
Shutoku's closing the gap!
Their style is different,
but they're like you.
（日向）形は違うけど—
似てんな オマエらと
They're like the light and shadow of Shutoku.
まるで秀徳の光と影だぜ あれは
You're right.
そうですね
しかし空中でパスをもらって
そのままスリー
But catching a pass mid-air
and making a three...
とんでもない技だな
That's an incredible move.
けど なぜここまで温存を？
But why are they holding back?
というより—
I think everything may be going
according to Midorima-kun's plan.
ここまでが緑間君が描いていた
シナリオだったんだと思います
帝光時代 キセキの世代は—
On Teiko, the Generation of Miracles
were forbidden from exercising
their full strength.
その力を全開にすることは
禁じられていました
It was because their bodies hadn't caught
up to the magnitude of their strength.
大きすぎる力に—
体がまだ
追いついていなかったためです
Though they all knew what
they were capable of,
お互いの手の内は知っていても—
no one has ever fought at full strength.
直接 本気で戦ったことは
ありません
In other words, this is Midorima's
first time experiencing the Emperor Eye.
つまり緑間も—
エンペラーアイを体感するのは
初めてだった
そして やはり—
He knew he couldn't win without gambling.
賭けに出なければ
勝てないと悟った
はい
Yes. Though the move is powerful
and effective against Akashi-kun,
あの技は赤司君に対して
強力かつ効果的ですが—
it's likely very risky, as well.
失敗するリスクも大きいはずです
けど賭けたかいは
あったんじゃねえか
But the risk was worth it.
その証拠に—
今までずっと涼しい顔してた
赤司の顔色が変わった
Look. Akashi's unconcerned
expression has changed.
Shutoku's not dead yet.
秀徳はまだ死んでいない
The game is just getting started.
勝負はこれからだ
想定以上だ 真太郎
This is more than I expected, Shintaro.
I couldn't ask for more.
そうでなくては
This is pointless.
（赤司）無駄だ どけ
Move!
My orders are absolute.
僕の命令は絶対だ
Midorima!
緑間！
More!
（緑間）まだだ
諦めるな
Don't give up!
There is no shame in falling!
倒れることなど 何も恥ではない
そこから
起き上がらないことこそ恥
The only shame is in not getting up!
赤司ー！
Akashi!
Impossible! How did he get
there from the ground?
バカな！
一度 倒れたあの体勢から？
一瞬で切り替えた
He changed plans in a second!
His judgment is terrifyingly fast!
状況判断も 恐ろしく早い
おりゃー！
（大坪）ええい！
What?
Otsubo!
大坪！
Otsubo-san, you're the best!
やっぱ大坪さん サイコーっスわ
You're not going anywhere!
（実渕(みぶち)）行かせないわよ！
（実渕）ウソでしょ
You're kidding, right?
通常のスリーでも
いい場面で なんて強気
He could've shot a normal three just now.
He's so confident.
（大坪）うおー！
（宮地）行けー！
Go!
Four in a row!
（観客１）４本連続！
Shutoku
Rakuzan
（観客２）洛山(らくざん)の背中 見えてきた
They're catching up to Rakuzan!
More!
（中谷(なかたに)）まだだ！ 当たれー！
Keep going!
They're making their move!
ここで来やがった
オールコートで
一気に勝負 かけてきた
They're going for a full-court press!
And Midorima and Takao are
double-teaming Akashi.
（伊月）しかも赤司には
緑間と高尾のダブルチーム
This pressure...
このプレッシャーは…
What are you doing?
（高尾）何やってんだ？ オマエ
そっちは自分のゴール
That's your own basket.
Wh-What did he...
な… 何を？
自殺点…
An own goal?
He was aiming for that.
狙って入れたぞ 今
何 考えてんだ？
What is he thinking?
Akashicchi...
赤司っち…
Akashi...
（根武谷）赤司…
When did I say you could let your guard down?
僕がいつ
気を抜いていいと言った？
The game isn't over yet.
試合はまだ 終わっていない
Did you relax after we
established a large lead?
一時 大差をつけたことで
緊張感が緩んだか？
I can tell because you were reeling after
they scored just a few baskets in a row.
たかだか数ゴール
連続で決められた程度で—
浮き足だったのが いい証拠だ
If the game were closer, you wouldn't
have disgraced yourselves in this way.
僅差であれば—
こんな ぶざまな姿をさらすことは
なかったはず
In that case, we should lose the gap.
ならば いっそ—
差など
なくなってしまったほうがマシだ
少し頭を冷やせ
Cool your heads.
But if we lose, you can
blame me all you want.
だが—
もし負けたら
好きなだけ僕を非難しろ
We will have lost because
of that shot I took.
敗因は僕の今のゴールだ
I will accept full responsibility
and quit the team.
全責任を負って 速やかに退部する
そして罪を償う証として—
To pay for my crime,
両の目をくり抜いて
オマエたちに差し出そう
I will gouge out my
eyes and give them to you.
I will gouge out my eyes
and give them to you.
両の目をくり抜いて
オマエたちに差し出そう
What are you talking about, Akashi?
（葉山）何 言ってんだよ 赤司
You don't need to do that!
そこまですることねえだろ
It's only if we lose.
（赤司）負けたらの話だ
If we win, there's no problem.
勝てば問題ない
心配などしていない
I'm not worried because I am certain.
なぜなら僕は 確信している
We cannot lose with you on the team.
オマエたちがいて
負けるはずがない
（高尾）
おいおい 部活のスポーツだぜ
Hey, this is just a high school team!
マジで目なんか
くり抜くわけねえだろ
There's no way he'd really
gouge his eyes out!
But why did the other guys react like that?
なのに何だよ？
今の他のヤツらのリアクションは
（火神）信じらんねえけど
赤司ならやりかねねえ
It's hard to believe,
but Akashi might really do it.
そういう危うさがヤツにはある
He's dangerous enough.
どっちにしろ—
Either way, it was an effective
way to inspire his team.
鼓舞としての効果は
絶大だったようだ
The expressions of the
Rakuzan players changed.
洛山の選手たちの顔つきが変わった
Shutoku
Rakuzan
Yeah!
おーっし！
Damn it!
クッソー！
Even though the gap has closed,
they're strong enough to hold them back.
点差を詰められても
きっちり突き放す地力の強さ
さすがに よどみないな
洛山の攻撃は
Rakuzan's attacks are relentless.
赤司の一声で完全に立ち直ったな
Akashi's speech got them back on their feet.
But Shutoku still has a chance.
だが まだ秀徳にもチャンスはある
いくら先が見えても—
He may be able to predict the future,
but he still can't stop Midorima's shots.
緑間のシュートは止められないはず
（赤司）残念だが—
Unfortunately,
この試合は もう終わりだ
this game is already over.
I have something to tell you.
宣言しよう
You will not even be able
to touch the ball again.
オマエはもう
ボールに触れることすらできない
What?
（緑間）何だと…？
不可能なのだよ 赤司
That's impossible, Akashi.
Not even your Emperor Eye can stop our shots.
たとえ オマエの
エンペラーアイでも—
オレたちのシュートは止められない
Height is certainly an important
factor in basketball.
（赤司）
確かにバスケットにおいて—
高さは重要なファクターだ
一見 絶対止められない
At first glance, it seems
as though I can't stop you.
But let me tell you something.
だが 教えてやろう
I am absolute.
絶対は僕だ
僕には先が すべて見えている
I see everything that will happen.
それを変えるなど
たやすいことだ
Changing it is easy.
なんか静かだな
It's quiet.
Shutoku's more cautious
than they've ever been.
秀徳も今までで
一番と言っていいくらい慎重だ
Of course they are.
当然だろう
They can't afford to make mistakes now.
今 この場面は
間違っても落とせない
連続スリーでついた勢いが—
Akashi just stopped the momentum they
gained from their consecutive threes.
赤司に失速させられたばかりだ
If they fail, they won't
have time to make up for it.
落とせば もう巻き返す時間はない
This moment will decide Shutoku's fate.
ここを決められるかどうかで—
秀徳の命運が決まる
（黒子）来る！
It's coming.
They're double-teaming Takao this time!
（火神）
今度は高尾にダブルチーム！
What?
（緑間）高尾！
Takao!
Such incredible pressure!
（小金井）すげープレッシャー
これじゃあ緑間の手元に
正確に出すなんて無理だ
It's impossible for him to pass
accurately into Midorima's hands now!
We knew you'd do this.
そんぐらいしてくるなんて
分かってたっつーの
You think I'd be Shin-chan's partner
if I lost my cool over this?
これくらいでテンパってて—
真ちゃんの相棒が務まるかよ
ナメんじゃねえよ！
Don't underestimate me!
He got past them!
（氷室）かわした！
（黄瀬）しかも緑間っちは—
And Midorimacchi's entering the motions!
モーションに入ってる
（火神）直前に動き出してた
He started moving just before Takao did.
He believed Takao would make it past them!
高尾が抜くと信じてやがった
（宮地･大坪）行けー！
Go!
（赤司）言ったはずだ
I told you.
絶対は僕だと
I am absolute.
Your shot has a weakness.
（赤司）
そのシュートには欠点がある
Because you're left-handed,
he has to pass from your left side.
左利きである真太郎の
シュートに合わせるには—
左側からしかパスを入れられない
And your shooting motion
is the same every time.
そして—
真太郎のシュートモーションは
いつも同じ
In other words, I can easily predict
つまりエンペラーアイなど
使わずとも—
the timing and path of the pass
even without my Emperor Eye.
パスコースもタイミングも
容易に分かるということだ
眼を使ったのは ほんの一瞬
I used my eyes for only a moment
so I could get a head start on
him at the moment of no return.
彼のパスより一歩早く—
かつキャンセルできない瞬間に
僕が動き出すため
ダブルチームも
わざとこちら側に向かせた
I intentionally let him slip past
the double-team on this side, too,
to close the distance between us.
僕との距離を縮めるために
（高尾）けど オレは赤司の位置を
ホークアイで認識してた
But I used my Hawk Eye to
confirm Akashi's position.
一歩早く動いたくらいじゃ
届かないはず
He shouldn't have been able to
reach it even if he got a head start.
まさか—
Could it be?
前半は わざとスピードを
緩めていたのか？
Did he intentionally slow himself
down during the first half?
真ちゃんも
ギリギリ気づかない範囲で？
Just barely enough so
Shin-chan wouldn't notice?
まさか布石は既に
打たれていたとはな
I hadn't realized you already
made your opening move.
You exceeded my expectations,
but not how I had imagined.
想定は超えていたが—
想像を超えていたわけではない
Shogi and basketball are the same.
将棋でもバスケでも同じだ
いつも言っていただろ？
Didn't I always tell you?
An opening move only works
相手に悟らせず
先を見据えてこその布石だ
when you plan ahead without
your opponent's knowledge.
（大坪）身体能力や才能に
頼るだけではない
He doesn't just rely on his
physical or mental capabilities.
恐ろしく緻密に
デザインされたプレー
He also has frighteningly
well-design strategies.
This is the captain of the Generation
or Miracles, Akashi Seijuro!
これが“キセキの世代”キャプテン
赤司征十郎か
（高尾）クソッ！ クソッ！
Damn! Damn!
Does this mean Akashi was in control
of everything that happened?
すべて…
ここまですべて—
赤司の手のひらの
上だったってことかよ
Don't give up!
（秀徳部員１）諦めんな！
（秀徳部員２）まだまだ行けるぞ
You can still do it!
Defense! Defense!
（秀徳応援団）ディーフェンス！
ディーフェンス！
Defense! Defense!
Sorry, but I don't like loud noises.
ごめんなさいね
うるさいのは苦手なの
Could you be quiet?
ちょっと静かにしてもらおうかしら
まだだ！ まだ終わってねえ
Not yet! It's not over yet!
打たすかよー！
You're not taking that shot!
待て 高尾！
Wait, Takao!
（高尾）フェイク…！
A fake!
He made a three while drawing a foul...
（高尾）
ファウルもらいながらスリー？
Could it be?
まさか…
ウソだろ
You're kidding, right?
I'm actually greedier than I look.
結構 欲張りなのよ
こう見えて 私って
A three-pointer and the basket counts.
スリー アンド バスカ
Seriously? That's a four point play.
マジか ４点プレーだ
All right!
おーっしゃー！
あり？
Huh?
No way. Yours always hurt.
あんたの痛いからイヤ
てか それ最初からやってよ
レオ姉
You should've started with that, Leo-nee.
だからぁ いつでも
できるわけじゃないんだってば
I told you, I can't do it anytime.
Shutoku
Rakuzan
（宮地）てぇーい！
（根武谷）おりゃー！
It's over, Shintaro.
終わりだ 真太郎
赤司ー！
Akashi!
改めて敬意を表する
I must express my respect for all
of you, Shintaro and Shutoku High.
真太郎 そして秀徳高校
Not a single one of you lost the
will to fight until the end.
最後まで—
誰１人 闘志を失わなかった
だが—
But you fell short.
届かない
Sleep now, veteran kings.
眠れ 歴戦の王よ
Kaijo
Seirin
Preview
This is Rakuzan's true strength...
（氷室）これが洛山の実力
Hey, can I leave now?
（紫原）
ねぇ オレもう帰っていい？
（氷室）決着が まだだろ
But they haven't played the finals yet.
（紫原）
うん… 決着したら帰っていい？
Can I leave once they do?
There's still another semifinal game.
I Can't Help But Laugh
（氷室）
準決勝は もう１試合あるだろ？
（氷室）あ… 敦？
Atsushi?!